Goblins can be dangerous in groups,
but I can use the layout of the dungeon
to force them into one-on-one fights,
where they're helpless against me.
I existential evolved into a ghoul,
and I've got some muscle now.
I'm much more agile than
I was as a skeleton.
And the biggest surprise was
that my mana, spirit energy,
and divinity have all increased.
Now I can strengthen not
only myself, but my sword.
Maybe... I'm even stronger
now than I was as a human!
The Rookie and
the Veteran
It's been so long since I've seen a human.
No, I can't go out there like this.
I'm a ghoul. She'd either
try to kill me or run away.
So I'll just watch from a distance.
I'm so jealous she gets to be human.
I don't recognize her. Is she a rookie?
I know pretty much every
adventurer in Maalt, actually.
The reason I know them is because
adventurers can be a rough crowd,
and a lot of them will make
fun of weaklings like me,
or try to get us to take the
fall for something they did.
Knowing their abilities and who
their friends are can help a lot.
Having fewer bad guys around made the
adventurers in Maalt a lot better than most.
And the guild seems to like having me around.
As weak as I am, hasn't
told me I need to retire.
That way leads to...
She's received proper training.
But she's weak, so she needs
to land a lot of hits.
She's probably planning on taking her
time and dodging while she defeats it...
But she's not watching
her surroundings at all.
I'm going to become a real adventurer!
I won't let a skeleton beat me!
I guess I've got no choice.
A ghoul?!
Come on... The enemy just turned
its back to you! Attack it!
No, I guess she's too stunned
to think about that.
Wow.
Um...
I'm glad you're safe...
H-Hello... I'm R-Rentt...
Rentt!
Stay away from me!
Please! Listen to me!
I'm not your enemy...
P-Please...
It's... talking?
Y-Yes!
I'm Rentt...
An adventurer...
An adventurer? An adventurer!
Yes!
I'm an adventurer!
My name is Rentt!
Rendo?
Renro... Rentt!
Rentt!
Yes!
So, why do you look like that, Rentt?
Some kind of disguise?
N-No! I died...
But... I'm alive!
Yes, you don't look like a normal monster.
Thank you for saving me.
Adventurers... look out for each other...
Um... I appreciate you saying that.
So... I hate to ask, but...
What?
Can I go back?
You're not going to kill me, right?
I-I'm not going to kill you...
But I want your help...
Help?
I want you... to buy me clothes.
Clothes?
I want to go back to Maalt.
Oh... so perhaps a robe
that would hide your body?
Thank you...
M-Money...
If you... buy me those clothes...
you can have the rest.
Please...
My name is Rina Rupaage.
As the daughter of a knight,
I shall repay this debt.
Just wait for me, Rentt...
She's pretty cautious around me.
For an adventurer, that's
the right way to be, but...
A proper adventurer would report
something as strange as a ghoul
like me to the guild immediately.
But I don't think she'll betray me.
Even if I'm wrong, though, I'll cross
that bridge when I come to it.
Excuse me!
Aren't you...?
You don't look hurt. I'm glad.
I was worried because you didn't
come back after sunset.
Well, a lot happened.
There's something I want
to ask you, actually...
I can't believe it... but I'm a lot
stronger than I was as a human.
It's not just that I'm stronger.
My body moves exactly how I want it to!
And I think my vision's better, too...
No, this is probably just what
they call combat intuition.
Something you can't learn
from training or studying.
So this is how the world looked to all
the adventurers that succeeded...
To think I only got the power I wanted
most after I ended up in this body...
Rentt?
Rentt, where are you?
S-She really came back...
Rentt!
Um... you're Rentt, right?
Or are you another ghoul, perhaps?
I'm Rentt.
Ghouls don't show up on the
early levels like this.
I see...
I feel like you've gotten a
little better at talking.
I-I practiced...
G-Great idea!
Oh, right. This is what you
asked for and your change.
S-Sorry... I'm still a little scared.
Give me a little more time... Just a
little more time until I get used to you!
No, it's fine...
Now, may I look at the clothes?
Of course! Go ahead!
Wow.
Do you like them?
Yes.
A plain color that nobody
would give a second glance,
and a robe that conceals the whole body,
like a mage would wear! Wonderful!
It's perfect!
I brought other things I
thought you might need.
I just got to Maalt, so I had someone
in the guild show me the best shops.
It felt like a bad idea to let
anyone see your arms or legs...
What a kind, considerate girl!
I feel like I could cry!
Except I physically can't!
Rentt?
No, it's nothing...
I'll try them on right away.
It's easier to move in this than I thought.
I lose some visibility, but it would be
easy enough to fight a monster or two...
How do you like them?
They're perfect.
Great!
You look pretty imposing,
too. Almost like a wight!
I stand out too much...
I guess that won't work.
Um, how about this?
What's this?
I thought it might be a bad idea for you to try to
go into town with your face looking like that.
Thank you...
When I first saw you, I thought
you were a rare or named monster.
A special type of monster,
huh? You may be right.
You look great!
I can't get it off.
No luck...
I'm sorry.
I saw it at a market stall and
couldn't stop thinking about it...
But looking back, it did
seem a little suspicious.
A market stall? Not a place
introduced by the guild?
It wasn't. The mask was the one thing
I bought at that market stall.
It was shockingly cheap.
How much?
Three coppers.
That's three loaves of bread.
Yeah, that's just too cheap.
I did check for curses! And nothing
happened when I touched it...
A curse that activates
when you put it on, huh?
I really do have the worst luck...
Let me try this out.
You can use divinity?!
Just a little...
Now that I have more divinity, I might
be able to break a basic curse.
I'm out of energy...
No luck?
I'm so sorry for bringing you a cursed item!
It's fine!
But it's all my fault!
Right now, I need to
hide my face anyway...
It responded to the divinity.
I just need to save up money and ask
a powerful cleric to break the curse.
So don't worry about it...
I'm sorry.
What...?
I can tell...
you're not a bad person.
So I'm not scared anymore!
I'm... not scared.
Thank you.
But you don't have to force yourself...
until the day when you really are used to me.
It won't take long at all!
It won't! I'm sure of it!
Now Rentt, let's head back to Maalt.
I registered as an adventurer
in the capital city guild.
But there are a lot of famous
adventurers there...
Since there weren't any
jobs for rookies like me,
they recommended I come to Maalt.
There are two labyrinths
close by, for one thing.
A good choice.
But I'm surprised you were willing to
come all the way out to the countryside.
I wanted to see the outside
world, and more than anything,
I want to get stronger and become
a full-fledged adventurer fast!
I understand how you feel. But it's better
for an adventurer to be a coward.
You've only got one life.
Yes!
Guys like me are pretty rare.
What's wrong?
A lot of people here know me.
They'll know something's
wrong if I show my ID.
Then shall we go in from a different gate?
Yes. One that's not normally used.
All right. We'll head to the west gate, then.
Rina, thanks.
I only made it this far thanks to you.
No, don't act like we're saying goodbye!
I'll help you as much as I can until
we get in town. No, even after that!
Yes, I do need someone to help me. But...
I'm a monster. If you help me get
inside, you'll be a criminal.
You might lose your adventurer's license.
I don't want to cause trouble for you.
Um...
If I hadn't met you, I'd be dead.
So at least once, I think it's okay
for me to risk my life for you!
Now let's go, Rentt!
We're about to close the gate!
Next!
A man and a woman?
Show us your IDs.
Adventurers?
Rentt Faina the bronze-class, and
Rina Rupaage the iron-class, right?
Fine.
You've got quite an unusual appearance.
Do I?
Have you seen him before?
You ever been to Maalt?
Let us see your face!
I'm sorry... His mask is cursed,
and he can't take it off!
Cursed?
Is that why he talks weird?
That's because he was horribly
injured after fighting a monster..
He bought the mask to hide the
scars, and it was cursed.
Now he can't take it off.
That's awful luck.
Try to pull it off yourself, please.
It's safe to touch!
I've touched it too.
Okay!
It really won't come off!
We need to donate a lot to the
church to have a cleric remove it.
And we're having trouble
saving up the money...
That's rough.
Fine! You may pass!
Okay, next!
We did it, Rentt!
It's all... thanks to you.
Thank you.
I'm just repaying the debt I owe you!
What's the plan now?
Huh? Rentt?
Rentt? Rentt?
Rentt? Where did you go?
She really is a good kid.
Her equipment's cheap, but
it's been well-maintained.
She has a knack for swinging that
sword, and she's pretty smart.
Brave, too.
She'll make a fine adventurer. I can tell.
All the people I know with talent like
that left me behind really fast...
I'm sorry. When I look a little
more human, I'll come apologize.
Now, it's hard to manipulate
a kind girl like Rina...
but I do need a human cooperator.
Somebody who's got a bit of a past,
and who can be trusted to keep secrets.
Lorraine...
Lorraine... wake up.
I said wake up!
Let me sleep just a little more...
I'll drop a book on your head.
Please don't do that...
Rentt, you...?!
Oh, it's just a mask.
Don't scare me like that.
Rentt... What happened?
The Undead Infiltrates the Town